<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata version="1.0">
  <uniqueid id="org.sil.fonts.AnnapurnaSIL.1.961" />
  <vendor name="SIL International" url="https://www.sil.org" />
  <credits>
    <credit
      name="Jonathan Coblentz, Sharon Correll, Peter Martin"
      url="https://software.sil.org/annapurna/"
      role="SIL font designers and engineers"
    />
  </credits>
  <description>
    <text lang="en">
      Annapurna SIL is a TrueType font with smart font capabilities added using
      state-of-the-art font technologies. This means that complex typographic
      issues such as the placement of combining marks or the formation of ligatures
      are handled by the font, provided you are running an application that provides
      an adequate level of support for one of these smart font technologies.
      
      Annapurna SIL has a calligraphic design that reflects the stroke contrast of
      writing the characters with a broad nib used for Devanagari.
      
      SIL International is the creator of the Annapurna SIL fonts, and is the owner
      of all proprietary rights therein.
      
      
      A Note Regarding the Open Font License
      ----------------------------------------------------
      
      The OFL prohibits the use of Reserved Font Names "Annapurna" and "SIL" in
      the name of any font that is derived from the Original Version of Annapurna
      SIL.
      
      
      ChangeLog
      ---------
      (This should list both major and minor changes, most recent first.)
      
      22 February 2019 (SIL WSTech team)  Annapurna SIL version 1.204
      - Reworked Graphite code to remove duplicates from substitution input classes.
      - Fixed Graphite bug involving alternate renderings of the half forms of ya.
      Fixed default rendering of dya.
      
      08 December 2017 (SIL NRSI team)  Annapurna SIL version 1.203
      - Matched OpenType with Graphite rendering where "ra halant ra halant" renders
      as "reph over ra-halant" instead of "eyelash ra" with reph over following cons.
      - Fixed Graphite bugs in reph position chaining rules
      - Fixed Graphite bug involving ta+ta conjunct half-form
      
      10 February 2017 (SIL NRSI team)  Annapurna SIL version 1.202
      - Fixed Graphite where reph was skipping the aakar after the ya
      - Used TTFautohint for hinting which solved disappearing candrabindu in Bold
      
      01 August 2016 (SIL NRSI team)  Annapurna SIL version 1.201
      - Fixed Graphite (reordering) issue when reph and ikar are in a cluster
      - Fixed Graphite issue related to TypeTuner fonts
      
      15 January 2015 (SIL NRSI team)  Annapurna SIL version 1.200
      - Added glyph U+0978 from the Devanagari block
      - Added half forms of all the consonant-rakar conjuncts
      - Fixed a near collision between Ha-Nukta and the uukar
      - Fixed many collisions of ekar/aikar over ra with a preceding upper mark
      - Hinting was done to enhance the on-screen rendering in Windows and Linux
      
      25 October 2012 (SIL NRSI team)  Annapurna SIL version 1.100
      - Added glyphs (with OpenType and Graphite support) from the Devanagari block
      *0900, 093A..093B, 094E..094F, 0955..0957, 0973..0977, 0979..097A
      - Added glyphs from the Devanagari Extended block
      *A8E0..A8FB
      - Added glyphs from the North Indic Number Forms block
      *A830..A839
      - U+dot (and UU+dot) is now attached under the Ra instead of the ligature version
      - Graphite feature IDs are now all four-character tags per CSS requirements
      - Minor bug fixes
      
      12 July 2011 (SIL NRSI team)  Annapurna SIL version 1.001
      - Added ligature glyphs and smart code support for minority languages
      * 0930 with 0941 and 093C
      * 0931 with 0941
      * 0931 with 0941 and 093C
      * 0930 with 0942 and 093C
      * 0931 with 0942
      * 0931 with 0942 and 093C
      - Fixed design bug in Bold font. The long I with nasal dot had a missing dot
      - Minor tweaks by adjusting attachment points and hinting parameters
      - Numerous bug fixes in Graphite
      
      31 Dec 2010 (SIL NRSI team)  Annapurna SIL version 1.0.0.0 (Version 1.000)
      - First version released under the SIL Open Font License
    </text>
  </description>
  <license url="https://scripts.sil.org/OFL" id="org.sil.ofl.1.1">
    <text lang="en">
      Copyright (c) 2007-2023, SIL International (https://www.sil.org/) with Reserved Font Names "Annapurna" and "SIL".
      
      This Font Software is licensed under the SIL Open Font License, Version 1.1. This license is copied below, and is also available with a FAQ at: https://scripts.sil.org/OFL
      
      
      -----------------------------------------------------------
      SIL OPEN FONT LICENSE Version 1.1 - 26 February 2007
      -----------------------------------------------------------
      
      PREAMBLE
      The goals of the Open Font License (OFL) are to stimulate worldwide development of collaborative font projects, to support the font creation efforts of academic and linguistic communities, and to provide a free and open framework in which fonts may be shared and improved in partnership with others.
      
      The OFL allows the licensed fonts to be used, studied, modified and redistributed freely as long as they are not sold by themselves. The fonts, including any derivative works, can be bundled, embedded, redistributed and/or sold with any software provided that any reserved names are not used by derivative works. The fonts and derivatives, however, cannot be released under any other type of license. The requirement for fonts to remain under this license does not apply to any document created using the fonts or their derivatives.
      
      DEFINITIONS
      "Font Software" refers to the set of files released by the Copyright Holder(s) under this license and clearly marked as such. This may include source files, build scripts and documentation.
      
      "Reserved Font Name" refers to any names specified as such after the copyright statement(s).
      
      "Original Version" refers to the collection of Font Software components as distributed by the Copyright Holder(s).
      
      "Modified Version" refers to any derivative made by adding to, deleting, or substituting -- in part or in whole -- any of the components of the Original Version, by changing formats or by porting the Font Software to a new environment.
      
      "Author" refers to any designer, engineer, programmer, technical writer or other person who contributed to the Font Software.
      
      PERMISSION &amp; CONDITIONS
      Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of the Font Software, to use, study, copy, merge, embed, modify, redistribute, and sell modified and unmodified copies of the Font Software, subject to the following conditions:
      
      1) Neither the Font Software nor any of its individual components, in Original or Modified Versions, may be sold by itself.
      
      2) Original or Modified Versions of the Font Software may be bundled, redistributed and/or sold with any software, provided that each copy contains the above copyright notice and this license. These can be included either as stand-alone text files, human-readable headers or in the appropriate machine-readable metadata fields within text or binary files as long as those fields can be easily viewed by the user.
      
      3) No Modified Version of the Font Software may use the Reserved Font Name(s) unless explicit written permission is granted by the corresponding Copyright Holder. This restriction only applies to the primary font name as presented to the users.
      
      4) The name(s) of the Copyright Holder(s) or the Author(s) of the Font Software shall not be used to promote, endorse or advertise any Modified Version, except to acknowledge the contribution(s) of the Copyright Holder(s) and the Author(s) or with their explicit written permission.
      
      5) The Font Software, modified or unmodified, in part or in whole, must be distributed entirely under this license, and must not be distributed under any other license. The requirement for fonts to remain under this license does not apply to any document created using the Font Software.
      
      TERMINATION
      This license becomes null and void if any of the above conditions are not met.
      
      DISCLAIMER
      THE FONT SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO ANY WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT OF COPYRIGHT, PATENT, TRADEMARK, OR OTHER RIGHT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDER BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, INCLUDING ANY GENERAL, SPECIAL, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF THE USE OR INABILITY TO USE THE FONT SOFTWARE OR FROM OTHER DEALINGS IN THE FONT SOFTWARE.
    </text>
  </license>
  <copyright>
    <text lang="en">
      Copyright (c) 2007-2023 by SIL International
    </text>
  </copyright>
  <trademark>
    <text lang="en">Annapurna SIL is a trademark of SIL International.</text>
  </trademark>
</metadata>